Hello English learners.
各位英语学习者，大家好。
Welcome back to another podcast here with us at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的播客节目。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是 Erika。
And today we have an advanced lesson for all of you and a very good one because we're going
今天我们为大家准备了一节高级课程，而且内容非常棒，因为我们要
to be talking about a very serious topic, global warming.
讨论一个非常严肃的话题：全球变暖。
That's right.
没错。
And you know, even though most people agree that global warming is a big problem, there's
而且你知道，尽管大多数人同意全球变暖是个大问题，但
still this sort of fringe element of people who believe that actually global warming doesn't
仍然有一小部分人认为全球变暖实际上并不
exist.
存在。
Exactly.
正是如此。
And that's what we're going to be looking at today.
这就是我们今天要探讨的内容。
But before we tell you more or less what the dialogue is about, let's take a look at some
但在我们大致介绍对话内容之前，先来看看一些
words in vocabulary preview.
词汇预览中的单词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We're going to look at two words here and you'll hear both of these in the dialogue.
我们要看两个词，这两个词你都会在对话中听到。
So the first one is polar ice caps.
第一个是“极地冰盖”。
Polar ice caps.
极地冰盖。
So when we talk about polar ice caps, polar is...
当我们说极地冰盖时，“极地”指的是……
Like the poles.
就像两极。
The poles, right?
两极，对吧？
The north and south poles of the earth.
地球的北极和南极。
Okay.
好的。
So the extreme...
所以是极端……
The top and bottom.
顶部和底部。
The top and bottom of the planet.
地球的顶部和底部。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And what about ice caps?
那“冰盖”呢？
So the polar ice caps are masses of ice that live or that exist on the top and the bottom
所以极地冰盖是存在于地球顶部和底部的
of the world.
大量冰块。
We have these big chunks of ice that are on the top at the bottom of the planet.
我们有这些大块的冰，位于地球的顶部和底部。
Yes.
是的。
They're there all year round.
它们全年都存在。
Okay.
好的。
So these are the polar ice caps.
这就是极地冰盖。
What about our next word?
下一个词是什么？
Well, next word is endangered species.
下一个词是“濒危物种”。
An endangered species.
濒危物种。
Okay.
好的。
So what is an endangered species?
那么什么是濒危物种？
It's a type of animal that is at risk of completely dying out.
它是一种面临完全灭绝风险的动物。
Okay.
好的。
So it's not completely extinct.
所以它还没有完全灭绝。
Right.
对。
So they're still...
所以它们仍然……
It's in danger.
处于危险中。
Okay.
好的。
In danger of.
面临……的危险。
Yeah.
是的。
So an example of endangered species would be...
那么濒危物种的例子有……
The Bengal tigers.
孟加拉虎。
Okay.
好的。
The tigers or the pandas.
老虎或熊猫。
Right.
对。
Or maybe gorillas.
或者大猩猩。
Right.
对。
So all of these animals, there are very few of them left in the world.
所有这些动物，世界上剩下的数量都非常少。
So they are endangered species.
所以它们是濒危物种。
Okay.
好的。
So with that, I think we're just about ready to turn to our dialogue.
那么，我想我们差不多准备好进入对话了。
Now here we're going to learn a lot of language that you can use when you want to make an
在这里，我们将学到很多语言，当你想要以学术方式
argument or express your point of view in a very sort of academic way.
提出论点或表达观点时可以使用。
But Marco, what are we arguing about here?
但是 Marco，我们在这里争论什么？
So we're going to listen as a college professor is lecturing about global warming and well,
我们将听到一位大学教授在讲授全球变暖，而
one of the students doesn't really agree with what he's saying.
其中一名学生并不同意他的说法。
And therefore, global warming is the greatest deception of the early 21st century.
因此，全球变暖是21世纪初最大的骗局。
Questions?
有问题吗？
Yeah.
有。
In the lecture you said there's more evidence in the scientific record supporting global
在讲座中，你说科学记录中有更多证据支持
cooling.
全球变冷。
Well, yes.
嗯，是的。
Essentially, the historical record supports a theory of climate cycles.
本质上，历史记录支持气候循环理论。
Warming and cooling are cooperating processes in the planetary ecosystem.
变暖和变冷是行星生态系统中的合作过程。
If that's true and the planet is getting cooler, what explains the rapid melting of the polar
如果那是真的，而且地球正在变冷，那如何解释极地冰盖的
ice caps and the dramatic rise in the global average temperatures?
快速融化和全球平均气温的急剧上升？
That are global temperatures rising.
全球气温正在上升。
If you look at the data from 1975, you'll-
如果你看1975年的数据，你会——
You'll be misled.
你会被误导。
If you were serious, you would look at the record starting in the 1880s.
如果你认真对待，你应该看从1880年代开始的记录。
Then you would see how dramatically the Earth's temperature has changed.
然后你就会看到地球温度发生了多么巨大的变化。
Young lady, I beg to differ.
年轻女士，恕我不同意。
Look, the point of the lecture was to emphasize that there's evidence for both sides.
听着，讲座的重点是强调双方都有证据。
And I'm putting forth the argument that there's greater evidence in support of the global
而我提出的论点是，有更多证据支持
cooling hypothesis.
全球变冷假说。
Look, it's an indisputable fact that the public is being manipulated and scared into believing
听着，这是一个无可争辩的事实：公众被操纵和恐吓，
that there's some kind of climate crisis.
相信存在某种气候危机。
This scaremongering is done quite simply for political reasons.
这种恐吓行为纯粹是出于政治原因。
But even without the uncomfortable reality that greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide
但即使不考虑温室气体（如二氧化碳）导致全球变暖这一令人不安的现实，
contribute to global warming, isn't the topic appropriate for politicians to discuss?
这个话题难道不适合政治家讨论吗？
Not if they want to use your tax dollars and mine to fund completely unnecessary initiatives.
如果他们想用你和我的税款来资助完全不必要的计划，那就不适合。
Yeah, like conservation, protecting endangered species, and investing in renewable energy.
是啊，比如保护、保护濒危物种和投资可再生能源。
At the very least, you have to concede that this debate has the potential to end our dependence
至少，你必须承认这场辩论有可能结束我们
on foreign oil.
对外国石油的依赖。
Buying oil supports autocratic countries that use these revenues to devastating ends.
购买石油支持了专制国家，这些国家将这些收入用于毁灭性的目的。
I've never been so disrespected in all of my days.
我这辈子从未受到过如此不尊重。
I'm a professor, a scientist, and a researcher of high regard.
我是一位教授、科学家和备受尊敬的研究员。
Yeah, and a duplicitous one at that.
是啊，而且还是个两面三刀的人。
Everyone knows you're in the pocket of the oil lobby.
谁都知道你被石油游说集团收买了。
Why should we trust your so-called findings more than tobacco institute studies, which
我们为什么要相信你所谓的发现，而不是烟草研究所那些
say smoking doesn't harm health?
说吸烟无害健康的研究？
You're full of it.
你满口胡言。
Some people just cannot handle civil debate.
有些人就是无法进行文明的辩论。
All right, so apparently this college professor is not very truthful in what he's saying,
好了，显然这位大学教授说的并不完全真实，
right?
对吧？
Well, yeah, maybe he believes it, but they certainly have very strong and differing opinions.
嗯，也许他相信这一点，但他们肯定有非常强烈且不同的意见。
So that's the interesting part is that we heard a lot of language that she used to argue
所以有趣的是，我们听到了她用来
her point of view.
论证自己观点的大量语言。
So this is interesting and we can start now looking at some of this language in Language
这很有趣，我们现在可以开始看看“语言要点”中的
Takeaway.
一些语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the college professor was arguing against this idea of global warming and she said,
这位大学教授在反驳全球变暖的观点，她说，
look, it's an indisputable fact.
“听着，这是一个无可争辩的事实。”
Okay, an indisputable fact.
好的，一个无可争辩的事实。
An indisputable fact.
一个无可争辩的事实。
Okay, so let's break it down and let's take a look at this word, indisputable.
好的，让我们分解一下，看看这个词，“无可争辩的”。
You can't argue against it.
你无法反驳它。
Okay, so something indisputable is you can't argue with it and will affect something that's
好的，所以无可争辩的东西是你无法争论的，并且会影响某件
true.
真实的事情。
Okay, so you can't argue with this piece of information.
好的，所以你无法与这条信息争论。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好的。
Indisputable fact.
无可争辩的事实。
So why don't we give a few examples?
那我们举几个例子吧？
It's an indisputable fact that China is the most populous nation on earth.
中国是世界上人口最多的国家，这是一个无可争辩的事实。
Okay, exactly.
好的，没错。
Or it's an indisputable fact that EnglishPod is the best podcast out there.
或者 EnglishPod 是最好的播客，这是一个无可争辩的事实。
Indeed, it is indisputable.
确实，这是无可争辩的。
All right.
好的。
So indisputable fact and what about our next word?
那么“无可争辩的事实”，下一个词是什么？
Well, the student accused the professor of scaremongering.
学生指责教授在“制造恐慌”。
Scaremongering.
制造恐慌。
Okay, now this is kind of a strange word, scaremongering.
好的，这是一个有点奇怪的词，“制造恐慌”。
Yeah, and I think some examples will help us to understand the meaning a little bit
是的，我认为一些例子会帮助我们更好地理解
better.
它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
Software flaws are not the same as virus attacks and saying otherwise is just scaremongering.
软件漏洞与病毒攻击不同，说相反的话只是在制造恐慌。
Example two.
例子二。
There's been a lot of scaremongering caused by the rumor that mobile phones cause cancer.
关于手机导致癌症的谣言引起了很多恐慌。
Okay, so basically we understand that it's kind of putting fear in people's minds.
好的，所以基本上我们理解它是在人们心中制造恐惧。
Yeah, it's sort of like selling fear for your own benefit.
是的，有点像为了自己的利益兜售恐惧。
Okay, so making people afraid for some objective or some purpose.
好的，所以为了某种目的或目标让人们害怕。
Yeah, and you know, this word reminds me of the word a fishmonger.
是的，而且你知道，这个词让我想起了“鱼贩”这个词。
Okay, a fishmonger.
好的，鱼贩。
What's that?
那是什么？
Which is basically a seller of fish.
基本上就是卖鱼的人。
So a scaremonger is a seller of fear.
所以“恐慌贩子”就是卖恐惧的人。
Okay, interesting.
好的，有意思。
So now we have a way of remembering it.
现在我们有了记住它的方法。
Yes.
是的。
Scaremongering.
制造恐慌。
All right, and moving on to our next word, we have autocratic.
好的，继续下一个词，我们有“专制的”。
Autocratic.
专制的。
An autocratic country.
一个专制国家。
So an autocratic country is ruled by someone who holds total power.
所以一个专制国家由拥有绝对权力的人统治。
Okay, so we have an autocratic country.
好的，所以我们有专制国家。
So basically we have a leader that rules everything, right?
基本上，我们有一个统治一切的领导人，对吧？
Right.
对。
So if we apply it not only to a country, we can say a person is autocratic.
如果我们不仅把它应用于国家，我们可以说一个人是专制的。
Yeah, you could say, I can't stand my boss's autocratic leadership style.
是的，你可以说，我受不了我老板的专制领导风格。
Or maybe a company.
或者也许是一家公司。
This company is a very autocratic organization.
这家公司是一个非常专制的组织。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And what about our last word?
最后一个词是什么？
The student accused the professor of being duplicitous.
学生指责教授是“两面三刀的”。
Okay, so she said he is duplicitous.
好的，所以她说他是两面三刀的。
Yes, duplicitous.
是的，两面三刀的。
All right, what does that mean?
好的，那是什么意思？
When you are duplicitous, you have behavior that is dishonest and is designed to trick
当你两面三刀时，你的行为是不诚实的，旨在欺骗
people.
他人。
Okay, so you're not a very honest person if you're duplicitous.
好的，所以如果你两面三刀，你就是一个不太诚实的人。
Yeah, you're telling lies as a means of making people do something or tricking them.
是的，你通过说谎来让人们做某事或欺骗他们。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a duplicitous person or a duplicitous idea maybe?
所以一个两面三刀的人，或者也许一个两面三刀的想法？
Okay.
好的。
All right, so these are all the words that we have on language takeaway today.
好的，这就是今天“语言要点”中的所有单词。
But now let's move on to some very interesting phrases that we can use to put forward some
但现在让我们进入“流利度构建”部分，看看一些
arguments in Fluency Builder.
可以用来提出论点的非常有趣的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay, and Marco, you actually just mentioned our first phrase, which is I'm putting forth
好的，Marco，你刚才提到了我们的第一个短语，“我提出的论点是”。
the argument that.
好的，所以“提出论点”。
Okay, so putting forth the argument that.
所以如果你提出一个论点。
So if you put forth an argument.
你呈现它。
You present it.
你呈现它或把它推向某人。
You present it or you push it towards somebody.
是的，你给出它。
Yeah, you give it.
所以我们只能提出论点吗？
So can we just put forth an argument?
实际上你可以提出很多东西，比如提出建议。
Well actually you can put forth a lot of things, like put forth a suggestion.
好的，我提出一个建议，我们应该买一台新电脑。
Okay, I'm putting forth a suggestion that we should get a new computer.
或者一个想法。
Or an idea.
Tim 提出了我们应该去夏威夷度假的想法。
Tim put forth the idea that we should go on vacation to Hawaii.
哦，好主意。
Oh, good idea.
好的，所以你可以提出很多不同的东西。
All right, so you can put forth many different things.
所以教授显然在提出全球变暖是神话的论点，
So the professor obviously is putting forth the argument that global warming is a myth
而学生显然完全不同意，她说“你必须承认这一点”。
and the student obviously totally disagreed and she said you have to concede that.
好的，“你必须承认这一点”。
Okay, you have to concede that.
你必须承认这一点。
You have to concede that.
All right, so this word concede or you have to concede.
好了，所以这个词是“concede”，或者说“你必须承认”。
Why don't we listen to some examples before we listen to the meaning.
在解释意思之前，我们先听几个例子吧。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm sorry, but I can't concede with you on this point.
抱歉，但在这一点上我不能同意你。
Example two.
例子二。
Julie conceded that she might have forgotten her sister's birthday.
朱莉承认她可能忘了她姐姐的生日。
Example three.
例子三。
Both philosophers conceded that their philosophies have some errors.
两位哲学家都承认他们的哲学存在一些错误。
Okay, so you have to concede that.
好的，所以你必须承认这一点。
Basically you have to agree that this one point in my argument is true.
基本上，你必须同意我论点中的这一点是真实的。
Maybe you're arguing many different points with somebody but you tell them, well, you
也许你在和某人争论很多不同的点，但你告诉他们，嗯，
have to concede that the earth is round.
你必须承认地球是圆的。
Okay, so that part I can't argue with.
好的，所以那部分我无法反驳。
It's really true.
这确实是事实。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So concede.
所以是“concede”。
Now, at the end of the dialogue, the student accused the professor of being in the pocket
现在，在对话的结尾，学生指责教授被石油游说集团
of the oil lobby.
收买了。
Okay, so he's in the pocket of.
好的，所以他是“in the pocket of”。
To be in the pocket of.
“To be in the pocket of”。
All right, so if I have somebody in my pocket, what does that mean?
好的，如果我把某人放在口袋里，那是什么意思？
It means basically you're bribing them.
基本上意味着你在贿赂他们。
Okay, so maybe I have the senator in my pocket.
好的，所以也许我把参议员放在口袋里。
Okay, so obviously you're paying the senator to do what you want.
好的，显然你是在付钱给参议员让他做你想做的事。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So it's another way, it's a very informal way of saying I'm bribing somebody or that
所以这是另一种说法，一种非常非正式的说法，表示我在贿赂某人，或者
person is being bribed.
那个人被贿赂了。
That's right.
没错。
So why don't we move to our final phrase.
那我们进入最后一个短语吧。
The student was talking about the professor's so-called findings.
学生在谈论教授所谓的发现。
Okay, so your so-called findings.
好的，所以你所谓的发现。
So-called.
“So-called”。
So this word so-called.
所以这个词是“so-called”。
You use this word when you want to take away from the importance of an idea.
当你想要削弱某个想法的重要性时，你会用这个词。
All right, so I use it before a noun, right?
好的，所以我把它用在名词前面，对吧？
Okay, so for example, my so-called friends.
好的，比如，我所谓的朋友。
Okay, so these friends are not really your friends maybe.
好的，所以这些朋友可能不是真正的朋友。
So yeah, they're friends in name but they don't act like friends.
是的，他们名义上是朋友，但行为不像朋友。
Okay, so you can say my so-called job.
好的，你可以说我所谓的工作。
Okay, so maybe you kind of go to work but do nothing all day.
好的，也许你只是去上班，但整天无所事事。
Right, or maybe you don't even really like what you do.
对，或者你可能根本不喜欢自己做的事。
Right.
没错。
Right, so my so-called job, my so-called friends or maybe my so-called teacher.
对，所以我所谓的“工作”，我所谓的“朋友”，或者我所谓的“老师”。
Okay, so this is a bad teacher.
好吧，所以这是个糟糕的老师。
Exactly.
正是。
So we use it a lot with many different nouns, right?
所以我们经常用它搭配很多不同的名词，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So that's our last phrase for fluency builder.
这就是我们流利度训练中的最后一个短语。
Now I think it'll help us to understand these words and phrases a little bit better to hear
现在，我认为通过再次在语境中听到这些单词和短语，
them again in context.
能帮助我们更好地理解它们。
And therefore global warming is the greatest deception of the early 21st century.
因此，全球变暖是21世纪初最大的骗局。
Questions?
有问题吗？
Yeah, in the lecture you said there's more evidence in the scientific record supporting
是的，在讲座中您提到科学记录中有更多证据支持
global cooling?
全球变冷？
Well, yes.
嗯，是的。
Essentially, the historical record supports a theory of climate cycles.
本质上，历史记录支持气候循环理论。
Warming and cooling are cooperating processes in the planetary ecosystem.
变暖和变冷是行星生态系统中的合作过程。
If that's true and the planet is getting cooler, what explains the rapid melting of the polar
如果那是真的，而且地球正在变冷，那如何解释极地冰盖的快速融化
ice caps and the dramatic rise in the global average temperatures?
和全球平均气温的急剧上升？
But are global temperatures rising?
但全球气温真的在上升吗？
If you look at the data from 1975, you'll...
如果你看1975年的数据，你会……
You'll be misled.
你会被误导。
If you were serious, you would look at the record starting in the 1880s.
如果你认真对待，你会看从1880年代开始的记录。
Then you would see how dramatically the Earth's temperature has changed.
然后你会看到地球温度变化得多么剧烈。
Young lady, I beg to differ.
年轻女士，我不同意。
Look, the point of the lecture was to emphasize that there is evidence for both sides.
听着，讲座的重点是强调双方都有证据。
And I'm putting forth the argument that there's greater evidence in support of the global
而我提出的论点是，有更多证据支持全球
cooling hypothesis.
变冷假说。
Look, it's an indisputable fact that the public is being manipulated and scared into believing
听着，这是一个无可争议的事实：公众被操纵和恐吓，相信
that there's some kind of climate crisis.
存在某种气候危机。
This scaremongering is done quite simply for political reasons.
这种危言耸听纯粹是出于政治原因。
But even without the uncomfortable reality that greenhouse gases like carbon dioxide
但即使不考虑像二氧化碳这样的温室气体导致全球变暖这一令人不安的现实，
contribute to global warming, isn't the topic appropriate for politicians to discuss?
这个话题难道不适合政治家讨论吗？
Not if they want to use your tax dollars and mine to fund completely unnecessary initiatives.
如果他们想用你和我的税款来资助完全不必要的计划，那就不适合。
Yeah, like conservation, protecting endangered species, and investing in renewable energy.
是啊，比如保护、保护濒危物种，以及投资可再生能源。
At the very least, you have to concede that this debate has the potential to end our dependence
至少，你必须承认这场辩论有可能结束我们对
on foreign oil.
外国石油的依赖。
Buying oil supports autocratic countries that use these revenues to devastating ends.
购买石油支持了专制国家，这些国家利用这些收入达到毁灭性的目的。
I've never been so disrespected in all of my days.
我这辈子从未受到过如此不尊重。
I'm a professor, a scientist, and a researcher of high regard.
我是一位教授、科学家，也是一位备受尊敬的研究员。
Yeah, and a duplicitous one at that.
是啊，而且还是个两面三刀的家伙。
Everyone knows you're in the pocket of the oil lobby.
谁都知道你被石油游说集团收买了。
Why should we trust your so-called findings more than tobacco institute studies, which
我们凭什么相信你那所谓的发现，而不是烟草研究所的研究，那些研究
say smoking doesn't harm health?
说吸烟无害健康？
You're full of it.
你满嘴胡扯。
Some people just cannot handle civil debate.
有些人就是没法进行文明的辩论。
All right, very good.
好了，非常好。
So interesting ways of putting forth arguments.
提出论点的方式挺有意思的。
And well, it's an interesting topic and very controversial, right?
嗯，这个话题很有趣，也很有争议性，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
But what I noticed in this dialogue is that the student was pretty assertive in putting
但我在这个对话中注意到，那个学生在提出论点并反驳老师时相当自信。
forth her argument and standing up to the teacher.
她敢于坚持自己的观点。
Right.
对。
And she was with the teacher a lot.
而且她跟老师争论了很多。
And this is interesting because it's a very cultural aspect, I think, right?
这很有意思，因为我觉得这很体现文化差异，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
In North American universities, there is this idea that it's really important to think critically
在北美大学里，有一种观念认为批判性思考非常重要，
and to argue against different ideas and to really speak up when you don't agree with
要敢于反驳不同的观点，当你不同意某件事时，
something.
要大胆说出来。
Right.
对。
So basically, there's this culture of questioning, not only what you're being taught, but you
所以基本上，这是一种质疑的文化，不仅质疑你所学的内容，
can also question the teacher.
还可以质疑老师。
You don't actually have to believe everything that the teacher is saying.
你不必全盘相信老师说的每一句话。
Exactly.
完全正确。
And I think this situation is really interesting.
我觉得这种情况真的很有意思。
You know, you always go to these lectures and there's always a question and answer period
你知道，你经常去听讲座，讲座结束时总会有
at the end of the lectures.
问答环节。
And I think that there's like this group of sort of academically minded people who feel
而且我觉得有一群学术头脑比较强的人，
like it's really cool to ask these really difficult questions and engage in arguments
他们觉得提出这些很难的问题、跟教授争论
with the profs.
是很酷的事。
Yeah, yeah, that's really true.
是啊，是啊，确实如此。
But actually, she used a lot of polite language and a lot of polite ways of actually arguing
但实际上，她用了很多礼貌的语言和礼貌的方式跟教授争论，
with the professor until the last point when she said, you're full of it.
直到最后她说“你满嘴胡扯”。
Yeah, you're full of it.
是啊，你满嘴胡扯。
Right.
对。
You're full of it.
你满嘴胡扯。
So what's she saying here?
她这里在说什么？
All right.
好吧。
She's basically saying that you're full of shit.
她基本上是在说你满嘴胡话。
So yeah, you wouldn't really say that.
所以是啊，你一般不会那么说。
So to be a little bit less rude, you would just say, you're full of it.
所以为了稍微不那么粗鲁，你可以直接说，“你胡说八道。”
Yeah.
是的。
But that is one step too far.
但那有点过头了。
I think this would be considered a little bit rude.
我觉得这会被认为有点粗鲁。
Yeah.
是的。
For a professor, yeah.
对教授来说，是的。
But I guess if you don't believe what your friend is telling you, or maybe he's exaggerating,
但我想如果你不相信朋友说的话，或者他可能在夸大其词，
you can say, oh, you're full of it.
你可以说，“哦，你胡说八道。”
Yeah.
是的。
So we've covered some great argumentative language here in this dialogue, but we want
所以我们在对话中涵盖了一些很棒的争论性语言，但我们想
to give you an opportunity to try out some of this language.
给你们一个机会来试试这些语言。
So come to our website at EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Right.
没错。
We are there to answer any questions or doubts, and we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里回答任何问题或疑惑，我们会在那里见你们。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
Until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
拜拜。